chapter 15
[Music]
this is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain For more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay hall
the Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 16 The Magic Art of the
Great Humbug Next morning the Scarecrow said to his friends: “Congratulate me I'm
going to Oz to get my brains at last.
When I return I shall be as other men are I've always liked you as you were,”
said Dorothy simply. “It is kind of you to like a Scarecrow,” he replied. “But surely
you will think more of me when you hear the splendid thoughts my new brain is
going to turn out.” Then he said goodbye to them all in a cheerful voice and went
to the Throne Room, where he rapped upon the door. “Come in,” said Oz. The Scarecrow
went in and found the little man sitting down by the window, engaged in deep
thought. “I have come for my brains,” remarked the Scarecrow, a little uneasily.
“Oh, yes; sit down in that chair, please,” replied Oz.
“You must excuse me for taking your head off, but I shall have to do it in order
to put your brains in their proper place.” “That’s all right,”
said the Scarecrow. “You are quite welcome to take my head off, as long as it will
be a better one when you put it on again.” So the Wizard unfastened his head and
emptied out the straw. Then he entered the back room and took up a measure of
bran, which he mixed with a great many pins and needles. Having shaken them
together thoroughly, he filled the top of the Scarecrow’s head with the mixture
and stuffed the rest of the space with straw, to hold it in place. When he
fastened the Scarecrow’s head on his body again he said to him, “Hereafter you
will be a great man, for I have given you a lot of brand-new brains.” The Scarecrow
was both pleased and proud at the fulfilment of his greatest wish, and
having thanked Oz warmly he went back to his friends. Dorothy looked at him
curiously. His head was quite bulged out at the top
brains. “How do you feel?” she asked. “I feel wise indeed,” he answered earnestly. “When I
get used to my brains I shall know everything.” “Why are those needles and pins sticking
out of your head?” asked the Tin Woodman. “That is proof that
he is sharp,” remarked the Lion. “Well, I must go to Oz and get my heart,” said the
Woodman. So we walked to the Throne Room and knocked at the door. “Come in,” called
Oz, and the Woodman entered and said, “I have come for my heart.” “Very well,”
answered the little man. “But I shall have to cut a hole in your breast, so I can
put your heart in the right place. I hope it won’t hurt you.”
“Oh, no,” answered the Woodman. “I shall not feel it at all.” So Oz brought a pair of
tenseness shears and cut a small, square hole in the left side of the Tin
Woodman’s breast. Then, going to a chest of drawers, he took out a pretty heart, made entirely
of silk and stuffed with sawdust. “Isn’t it a beauty?” he asked. “It is, indeed!”
replied the Woodman, who was greatly pleased. “But is it a kind heart?” “Oh, very!”
answered Oz. He put the heart in the Woodman’s breast and then replaced the
square of ten soldering it neatly together where it had been cut. “There he
said now you have a heart that any man
might be proud of I am sorry that I had
to put a patch on your breast, but it really couldn’t be helped nevermind the
patch,” exclaimed the happy Woodman. “I am very grateful to you, and shall never
forget your kindness.” “Don’t speak of it,” replied Oz. Then the Tin Woodman went
back to his friends, who wished him every joy on account of his good fortune. The
Lion now walked to the Throne Room and knocked at the door. “Come in,” said Oz. “I
have come for my courage,” announced the Lion, entering the room. “Very well,”
answered the little man; “I will get it for you.” He went to a cupboard and
reaching up to a high shelf took down a square green bottle, the contents of
which he poured into a green gold dish, beautifully carved. Placing this before
the Cowardly Lion, who sniffed at it as if he did not like it, the Wizard said: “Drink.”
“What is it as the Lion. “Well,” answered Oz, “if it were inside of you, it would be
courage. You know, of course the courage is always inside one; so that this really
cannot be called courage until you have swallowed it. Therefore I advise you to
drink it as soon as possible.” The Lion hesitated no longer, but drank till the
dish was empty. “How do you feel now?” asked Oz. “Full of courage,” replied the Lion, who
enjoy philippe act to his friends to tell them of his good fortune. Oz, left to
himself, smiled to think of his success and giving the Scarecrow in the Tin
Woodman and the Lion exactly what they thought they wanted. “How can I help being
a humbug,” he said, “when all these people make me do things that everybody knows
can’t be done? It was easy to make the Scarecrow in the Lion and the Woodman
happy, because they imagined I could do anything. But it will take more than just
imagination to carry Dorothy back to Kansas, and I’m sure I don’t know how it